<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<indexing>
 <paragraph index="7" node_type="writer">Lab 3: CrowdStrike Case Study. Anastasiia Tiurina (22401247)</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="19" node_type="writer">Lab 3: CrowdStrike Case Study</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="22" node_type="writer">CrowdStrike Case Study Report</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="23" node_type="writer">Anastasiia Tiurina</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="24" node_type="writer">School of Innovation, Design and Technology Whitireia</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="25" node_type="writer">IT8x16 Network Design and Management</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="26" node_type="writer">Supervisor: Dr. Bryce Antony</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="29" node_type="writer">Overview</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="30" node_type="writer">On 19th of July many companies found that their working machines as well as devices, running on Windows, were down with the BSOD error. The work of airports and hospitals across the world was disrupted due to the same error. The cause of the global outage was a scheduled update of Falcon Sensor software created by CrowdStrike company. Before the CrowdStrike managed to roll back the faulty update the damage has already been done.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="31" node_type="writer">What was the function of the CrowdStrike Application effected?</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="32" node_type="writer">Falcon is the application that received a buggy update which disabled millions machines across the world. According to the official application page it provides an endpoint protection.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="33" node_type="writer">What was the business objective / goal that the effected CrowdStrike application addressed?</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="34" node_type="writer">The goal of the Falcon software is to protect the network of an organization from cyberattacks and malware. It is an implementation of Endpoint Detection and Response (EDR) cybersecurity technology. Endpoint in this context is a device within the network. The activity on an endpoint is constantly monitored by the installed agent – in this case it is a Falcon Sensor, - and, according to the official site of CrowdStrike, the collected data is sent to the monitoring system in the cloud where it is analysed. </paragraph>
 <paragraph index="35" node_type="writer">So, the business goal of the Falcon is to prevent security breaches and ensure that the company or business that uses Falcon platform follows the CIA triad concept. Such precautions can avoid cases like Latitude breach in Australia.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="36" node_type="writer">How did this 'cause' the outage?</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="37" node_type="writer">Early release and badly tested patch.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="38" node_type="writer">Technology-wise, CrowdStrike published a report with the details with Falcon-specific terminology.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="39" node_type="writer">Rapid Response Content (RRC) is threat intelligence and it is stored in the cloud.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="40" node_type="writer">Falcon Sensor has:</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="41" node_type="writer">Sensor Content: contains rules for threat detection</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="42" node_type="writer">Sensor Detection Engine: acts according to rules and data from RRC</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="43" node_type="writer">Content Interpreter: receives RRC and interprets it through its regex engine and then it goes to Content Validator.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="44" node_type="writer">RRC is sent to Interpreter through Channel File that has Template Type.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="46" node_type="writer">Before the update Interpreter was accepting 20 parameters. During the update they added one more Template, adding one more parameter. However, there was an error in regex engine that did not parse the parameter correctly. This caused the discrepancy in amount of parameters going through Channel File and number of parameters the Interpreter reads from. Hence, the Interpreter addressed 21st element in an array of size 20, thus, causing element out-of-bound error.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="48" node_type="writer">Why it caused BSOD: </paragraph>
 <paragraph index="49" node_type="writer">The Falcon Sensor works on the level of kernel drivers (Weston, 2024). And errors in kernel-mode drivers cause crash of operating system (Microsoft, 2023).</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="50" node_type="writer">The program (third-party software) resides in the critical path of the system. Therefore, if it fails the entire system fails.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="51" node_type="writer">As a Network Infrastructure Manager, what could you have changed in the Network Design to mitigate the effects of the outage.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="52" node_type="writer">Point of view: CrowdStrike</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="53" node_type="writer">Adding machines or VMs that can be used for testing of the patch installation.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="54" node_type="writer">In case of disaster recovery testing is the most important. And in their Root Cause Analysis CrowdStrike claimed that they tested the fix for the buggy patch and enhanced their testing procedures.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="55" node_type="writer">Point of view: Business that uses Falcon</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="56" node_type="writer">The strategy and disaster recovery plans depends on business goal of the company and understanding the crucial parts. </paragraph>
 <paragraph index="57" node_type="writer">What protocols / procedures / practices could have been added to enhance resilience in this case study.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="58" node_type="writer">Point of view: CrowdStrike</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="59" node_type="writer">Enhance testing practices.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="60" node_type="writer">Point of view: Business that uses Falcon</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="61" node_type="writer">In this particular case turning the auto-updates off would have helped. However, updating the installed software is important for security reasons. Having emergency/spare machines. Creating restoration images or VM backups.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="62" node_type="writer">References:</paragraph>
 <object index="63" name="ZOTERO_BIBL {&quot;uncited&quot;:[],&quot;omitted&quot;:[],&quot;custom&quot;:[]} CSL_BIBLIOGRAPHY RNDFnINSdbZF4" object_type="section"/>
 <paragraph index="64" node_type="writer" parent_index="63">Microsoft. (2023, December 16). User Mode and Kernel Mode—Windows drivers. https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-hardware/drivers/gettingstarted/user-mode-and-kernel-mode</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="65" node_type="writer" parent_index="63">Weston, D. (2024, July 27). Windows Security best practices for integrating and managing security tools. Microsoft Security Blog. https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/security/blog/2024/07/27/windows-security-best-practices-for-integrating-and-managing-security-tools/</paragraph>
</indexing>
